<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Main Page</title>
    <link>https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Go to Main Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 11:15:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Kaggle Competition</title>
      <link>https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>In this competition I was challenged to predict the package delivery time by small transportation vans. This was an individual competition between 50 students from the Master in Business Analytics and Big Data at IE University with the duration of 4 hours. The evaluation metric for this competition was the MAE (Mean Absolute Error) and we were allowed to use Dataiku, R or Python. I used Python, did some feature engineering and my final XGBoost model finished in 3rd place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Bike Sharing Prediction</title>
      <link>https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>In this assignment from the Statistical Programming in Python course I predicted the total number of Washington D.C. bicycle users on an hourly basis using a dataset (&amp;ldquo;hour.csv&amp;rdquo;) with data from 2011 and 2012.
Part 1: Exploratory Data Analysis 1.1. Ensuring data quality
1.2. Plotting clear and meaningful figures
1.3. Checking possibly redundant variables via correlations
1.4. Giving insights on what seems relevant for prediction and what does not
Part 2: Data Engineering 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Football Passes Network</title>
      <link>https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>In this assignment from the Social Network Analysis course I used Python to explore key concepts of graph theory using football matches open data from Statsbomb.
Part 1: Introduction Football should not be simply analyzed and explained by capturing and interpreting the classical individual player&amp;rsquo;s metrics and abilities. Football is complex and its complexity makes individually collected data unproductive to interpret accurately a team&amp;rsquo;s performance. Football is a sport where all the team players can be considered as a complex network whose nodes (players) interact with the aim of overcoming the opponent network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Titanic Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>In this assignment from the Statistical Programming in Python course I performed an exploratory analysis of the Titanic dataset ( https://www.kaggle.com/c/titanic/data) and implemented a strategy to impute missing values.
Part I: Exploratory Analysis Exploratory data analysisis (EDA) is an approach to analyzing datasets to summarize their main characteristics, often employing data visualization methods.
Import Python Libraries import pandas as pd import numpy as np import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import seaborn as sns %matplotlib inline Point 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrolousantos.github.io/Pedro_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>   Platform URL     LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pedrolousantos   GitHub: https://github.com/pedrolousantos   Email: pedrolsantos1@hotmail.com    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
